Rockefeller University Press, Ingests, post-1982 FA973
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University Press, Ingests, post-1982
1911, 1956-1980
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University Press
FA973
3.93 Cubic Feet 3 standard record storage boxes.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
File Plan
Former Classification: I 580-U
Arrangement
As received.
Scope and Contents
Primarily consists of correspondence, permission documentation, and Rockefeller Institute/Rockefeller University Calendar of Events.
- Original mss for "Beyond Tomorrow: Trends and Prospects in Medical Science" (Box 1)
- Bronk memorial, 1976 (Box 1)
- Bronk, Dr. Detlev W., 1956, 1973, 1975, 1976 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  DWB biographical and obituary materials. Also includes 1975 David Rockefeller/RU, re resignation as Chairman, RU Board of Trustees and appointment of Patrick E. Haggerty.
- Christmas Lectures, 1975, 1977 (Box 1)
  Tapes of Christmas lectures, and tapes of other lectures at RU (1962-1975).
  Conditions Governing Access
  RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
- Corner, George W. Autobiography, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
- Sequel to Corner history, 1978 (Box 1)
- Delbruck, Max Correspondence, 1977-1978, 1980 (Box 1)
- Delbruck, Max, 1977 (Box 1)
  Includes final version of Delbruck ms, "Mind from Matter?".
- Hill, A.V., "Ethical Dilemma of Science", Japanese edition., 1959, 1971-1978 (Box 1)
- Financial: 97.146 Ethical Dilemma: Hill: Bills, Correspondence, 1959-1969, 1974 (Box 1)
- The Greatest Adventure - Promotion, primarily 1974 (Box 1)
- The Greatest Adventure - National Science Foundation (NSF) Grant, 1969, 1971-1975 (Box 1)
- The Greatest Adventure - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
- The Greatest Adventure - Presentation Copies, 1973-1975 (Box 1)
- The Greatest Adventure - Permissions, 1972-1979 (Box 1)
- Manuscript on Homeopathy, 1911 April 27 and May 19 (Box 1)
  Frederick T. Gates/JDR Sr., with enclosure re: Homeopathy.
- J-5 Lipid Research, 1963, 1966, 1970 (Box 1)
  re: Journal of Lipid Research. Includes re: Biophysical Journal trademark.
- Miller, George "Verbal Machinery of Thinking", 1977-1979 (Box 1)
  AEM Christmas Lectures, 1977. Includes correspondence, mss, newspaper and journal clippings.
- Miller, George Christmas Lectures. "Verbal Machinery of Thinking", 1977 December (Box 1)
  Mss of Introduction and Lectures I, II, III, IV and correspondence.
- Permissions - A History of the Rockefeller Institute: Corner, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
- Permissions - Atmosphere and the Sea in Motion, 1977, 1979 (Box 2)
- Permissions - Baker, William O., 1980 (Box 2)
- Permissions - Beyond Tomorrow, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
- Permissions - Glass, David C. editor. Environmental Influences Vol III. Neurophysiology and Emotion Vol I. Genetics Vol II., 1970-1979 (Box 2)
- Permissions - The Ethical Dilemma of Science, 1971 (Box 2)
- Permissions - Heraclitean Fire, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
- Permissions - International Cell Biology, 1977-1979 (Box 2)
- Permissions - Journals and Miscellaneous, 1977, 1979 (Box 2)
- Permissions - Law and the Social Role of Science, 1975, 1977, 1979 (Box 2)
- Permissions - The Neurosciences I, 1970-1979 (Box 2)
- Permissions - The Neurosciences II, 1972-1979 (Box 2)
- Permissions - Oflaction and Taste, 1971-1979 (Box 2)
- Permissions - Paired Pulse, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  Stimulation of the Heart.
- Permissions - The Professor, The Institute and DNA., 1976-1978 (Box 2)
- Permissions - Rockefeller Institute Review, 1976, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
- Permissions - Science and the Evolution of Public Policy, 1973-1974, 1976 (Box 2)
- Permissions - Science and the Human Condition in India and Pakistan, 1971 (Box 2)
- Permissions - The Scientific Endeavor, 1970, 1972-1974 (Box 2)
- Permissions - Studies on Excitation and Inhibition in the Retina, 1978 (Box 2)
- Permissions - The Unseen World, Dubos., 1976m 1978 (Box 2)
- Permissions - Warner Modular Publications, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
- Permissions - Xerox Individual Publishing (XIP) Program, 1972-1974 (Box 2)
- Permissions - Year 1970 (Granted 100 words or less. For various RU publications) (Box 2)
- Permissions - Year 1971 (Granted 100 words or less. For various RU publications) (Box 2)
- Permissions - Year 1972 (Granted 100 words or less. For various RU publications) (Box 2)
- Permissions - Year 1973 (Granted 100 words or less. For various RU publications) (Box 2)
- Rous, Peyton Memorial, 1970-1979 (Box 2)
  Booklet, 1970-1972; Centennial, 1978-1979.
- Rockefeller University 75th Anniversary, 1973 May-1975 (Box 2)
- Calendar of Events, 1957 September-1980 December; 23 folders. (Box 3)
  RI Calendar of Events until June 1965. RU Calendar of Events thereafter.